Guide to the Gil J Wolman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Professional Papers, 1952-2008; Series V; 2.93; (8 boxes)
  - Exhibition and Trade Publications, 1960-2008
    - Robin, A., Essai d'histoire comparée du lettrisme, de l'informel-à-signes et de quelques peintres-à-signes indépendants pamphlet, 1963- (Box 40, Folder 567)
      Preface text to the exhibition La lettre et le signe dans la peinture contemporaine (Galerie Valérie Schmidt).
    - Rodolphe Stadler Paris, Lettrisme & hypergraphie brochure, 1964- (Box 40, Folder 568)
      Two versions: general circulation brochure, and numbered copy 51/70.
    - Galerie de la librairie anglaise, Dessins hypergraphiques de Altmann, Sabatier, Spacagna brochure, 1965- (Box 40, Folder 569)
      "Catalogue invitation" with signed original artworks from Altmann, Sabatier, and Spacagna. Numbered copy 19/20.
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts (London, England), Between Poetry and Painting catalog, 1965- (Box 40, Folder 570)
    - Musée national d'art moderne, Salle lettriste et hypergraphique brochure, 1968- (Box 40, Folder 571)
    - 25ème Salon des réalités nouvelles catalog, 1971- (Box 41, Folder 572)
    - Galerie Cyrus 71, Espaces autres: ensembles de signes brochure, 1972- (Box 41, Folder 573)
    - Mec-art graphic brochure, 1972- (Box 41, Folder 574)
    - Théâtre le palace, Pour une rencontre dossier, 1972- (Box 41, Folder 575-576)
      Anthology of select texts for the poetry reading event.
    - Galerie de la Halle-au-Blé, Aspects de la l'art actue l brochure, 1974- (Box 41, Folder 577)
    - Laude, André, Claude Boujon: La naissance blanche, 1974- (Box 41, Folder 578)
      Introductory text for the Galerie L'Oeil de boeuf exhibition.
    - Salon international d'art actuel Bruxelles catalog, 1974- (Box 41, Folder 579)
    - Heidsieck, Bernard, Poésie sonore/Poésie action 1955-1975 (Box 41, Folder 580)
      Introductory text for the event Panorama de la poésie sonore at the Atelier Exposition Annick Le Moine, 1976.
    - Jeannet, Monnaie d'artiste: Le livre des factures, 1976- (Box 41, Folder 581)
    - Centro culturale d'arte contemporanea Antiope, Maestri contemporanei 1976-1977 gallery catalog (Box 41, Folder 582)
    - Shakespeare & Co. bibliography on Untel (Group of artists), [1977] (Box 41, Folder 583)
    - Maison pour Tous de Mortagne-au-Perche, Êtes-vous sûr de bien voir? brochure, 1979- (Box 41, Folder 584)
    - McCaffery, Steve and B. P. Nichol, Sound poetry: a catalogue for the eleventh International Sound Poetry Festival, [1979] (Box 41, Folder 585)
      Photocopies of select pages.
    - Museum Moderner Kunst, Hahn Collection catalog, 1979- (Box 41, Folder 586)
    - Premier festival international de la carte postale d'avant-garde, Ca(r)talogue 1, 1979- (Box 41, Folder 587)
      Numbered copy 452/1000.
    - Galerie Bar de l'Aventure, Prenez un livre, dit-elle exhibition catalog, 1980- (Box 41, Folder 588)
    - Noguez, Dominique, Treize ans de cinéma experimental en France (1966-1979) preface text and program, 1980- (Box 41, Folder 589)
    - Foire internationale d'art contemporain catalog, 1981- (Box 42, Folder 590)
    - Yacoël, Yves, L'électrographie dans le métro catalog, 1982- (Box 42, Folder 591)
      Numbered copy 19/30.
    - Centre Georges Pompidou, Pour François Dufrêne, 1983- (Box 42, Folder 592-593)
    - Galerie de l'Ancienne Poste, Wolman catalog, 1983- (Box 42, Folder 594)
    - Musée-château d'Annecy, Papier: Détournements volontaire s exhibition catalog, 1983- (Box 42, Folder 595)
    - Galerie du Centre d'action culturelle Pablo Neruda, Livres-Objects: Le livre dans tous ses états exhibition catalog, 1984- (Box 42, Folder 596)
    - Galerie Spiess, La forme exhibition catalog, 1984- (Box 42, Folder 597)
    - Malmö Konsthall, New Media 2, 1984- (Box 42, Folder 598)
    - Polyphonix 10 festival program, 1986- (Box 42, Folder 599)
    - Yves Gevaert, bookseller's bulletin no. 13, circa 1986 (Box 42, Folder 600)
    - Letaillieur, François for Galerie 1900-2000, Le demi-siècle lettriste exhibition catalog, 1988- (Box 42, Folder 601)
    - Centre Georges Pompidou, Sur le passage de quelques personnes […] à propos de l'internationale situationniste brochure, 1989- (Box 42, Folder 602)
    - Galerie 1900-2000, Pinot Gallizio: Le situationnisme et la peinture, 1989- (Box 42, Folder 603)
      With autograph dedication to Wolman by Giorgio Gallizio.
    - Paule-Léon Bisson-Millet, bookseller's catalogs no. 8-9, and unnumbered, circa 1989 (Box 42, Folder 604)
    - Association pour la recherche sur le cancer, Vente aux enchères au profit de l'ARC auction catalog, 1991- (Box 42, Folder 605)
    - Musée d'art contemporain de Dunkerque, auction catalog for Doctors Without Borders, 1991- (Box 43, Folder 606)
    - Centre national des arts plastiques, Poètes plasticiens artists' biographies, 1992- (Box 43, Folder 607)
    - Galerie de Paris. La parole haute - supplément d'un journal qui n'existe pas, oversize pamphlet, 1993 (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 771)
    - Centre Georges Pompidou, Hors limites program, 1994- (Box 43, Folder 608)
    - Fondation Cartier pour l'art contemporain, Raymond Hains: Les 3 Cartier exhibition brochure, 1994- (Box 43, Folder 609)
    - Galerie Weiller, Claude Clavel - L'ascension d'Icare, 1994- (Box 43, Folder 610-611)
      Exhibition catalog, and brochure on Clavel's career, featuring texts by Wolman and Alexis Violet.
    - Salon de Mars catalog, 1994- (Box 43, Folder 612)
    - Rémi Adler commissaire priseur, Tableaux des XIXe et Xxe siècles - dessins - estampes - sculptures - art contemporain, 1995- (Box 43, Folder 613)
    - Secours populaire français, 500 petits tableaux pour une grande cause sale catalog, 1995 (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 752)
    - Casino Luxembourg, Faiseurs d'histoire artists' biographies, 1999- (Box 43, Folder 614)
    - Musée d'art moderne de Saint-Étienne, Après la fin de l'art brochure, 2003- (Box 43, Folder 615)
    - Centre international de poésie Marseille, Le cahier du refuge 173: Gil J Wolman, 2008- (Box 43, Folder 616)
      Special issue for the C.I.P.M. exhibition Gil J Wolman: Éditions inconnues, disques et documents.
    - Levin, Tom for Exit Art, "The Situationist International 1957-1972: Images, Tracts and Texts" introductory text, undated (Box 43, Folder 617)
    - Librairie-galerie Les mains libres, bookseller's catalog no. 7, undated (Box 43, Folder 618)
    - Maison de la culture du Havre catalogs, undated (Box 43, Folder 619)
  - Ephemera, 1963-2008
    Small ephemera for specific exhibitions is listed chronologically under the heading "Flyers and invitation cards by event". Other ephemera files follow, listed alphabetically.
    - Flyers and invitation cards by event
      - Galerie Valérie Schmidt, Art Scotch, 1964- (Box 43, Folder 620)
        Accompanied by an holograph introductory text to the exhibition.
      - Galerie Valérie Schmidt, Wolman introspective (1950-1970) (Box 43, Folder 621)
      - Galerie Valérie Schmidt, Main basse sur la vi, 1972- (Box 43, Folder 622)
      - Galerie Weiller, Ex-position Wolman, 1973- (Box 43, Folder 623)
      - Galerie Oeil de Boeuf, Otto portraits, 1975- (Box 43, Folder 624)
      - Galerie Weiller, Quelques jours en août 1976, 1977- (Box 43, Folder 625)
      - Galerie Weiller, C'est le mouvement séparatiste qui provoque l'espace, 1978- (Box 43, Folder 626)
        Accompanied by an holograph draft of the press release.
      - L'exposition impossible de Wolman, 1978- (Box 43, Folder 627)
      - Galerie Lara Vincy, Wolman s'en séparer?, 1980- (Box 43, Folder 628)
      - Galerie Weiller, La décomposition, 1980- (Box 43, Folder 629)
      - Centre Georges Pompidou, La revue parlée, 1982- (Box 43, Folder 630)
      - Galerie Spiess, W La libertà, 1982- (Box 43, Folder 631)
      - Galerie Lara Vincy, Imaginez une exposition, 1983- (Box 43, Folder 632)
      - Galerie Nane Stern, Faux Wolman de Wolman, 1984- (Box 43, Folder 633)
      - Foire internationale d'art contemporain, Peinture fermée, [1989] (Box 44, Folder 634)
      - Galerie de Paris, Peinture dépeinte, 1991- (Box 44, Folder 635)
      - Galerie de Paris, Les inhumations, 1993- (Box 44, Folder 636)
    - Ephemera file "Gil vernissage - divers cartons d'invitation", 1973-1995 (Box 44, Folder 637)
      Most items in this original grouping are duplicates of invitation cards.
    - Ephemera file "Invitations W", 1960-1990 (Box 44, Folder 638)
      Includes photocopies of articles referring to Wolman, in addition to exhibition ephemera.
    - Ephemera file loaned to the Centre international de poésie Marseille in 2008, 1964-1980 (Box 44, Folder 639)
      Items sent to the C.I.M.P. for the 2008 exhibition Gil J Wolman: Éditions inconnues, disques et documents. Includes duplicates of invitation cards and press releases, as well as a brochure for a sound poetry event held at the Musée d'art moderne de la ville de Paris on 1967 June 08.
    - Invitation cards for miscellaneous solo exhibitions, 1974-1995 (Box 44, Folder 640)
    - Invitation cards for miscellaneous collective exhibitions, 1963-2007 (Box 44, Folder 641-646)
    - Invitation cards for other artists' exhibitions, 1963-1995 (Box 44, Folder 647)
    - Flyer for Cannes Film Festival screenings, 1952 (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 753)
    - Flyers for events and performances, 1969-1995 (Box 44, Folder 648)
    - Posters for events, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 649)
      Contains Théâtre le Palace, Jacob ou la persuasion (1974), and Galerie Noire, La foire aux artistes (1975).
    - Posters for Galerie Valérie Schmidt, Dissolution et reconstitution du mouvement, 1968 (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 772)
    - Posters for Jacob ou la persuasion exhibitions, 1971-1976 (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 773)
      Exhibitions of the artists' collective founded in 1971 by Hermann Amann at Galerie Messine (1971) and Galerie L55 (1976).
    - Posters for solo and collective exhibitions, 1978-2008 (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 786-787)
      Contains Galerie Spiess, Espaces nouveaux (1978) and Amann, Weber, Wolman (1979), Galerie de Seine, Art sujet (1980), Galerie Bar de l'Aventure, Prenez un livre, dit-elle... (1980), Galerie de l'ancienne poste, Wolman [1983], Pour la poesie (1992), Centre international de poésie Marseille Gil J Wolman: Éditions inconnues, disques et documents (2008).
    - Posters for solo and collective exhibitions, 1974-1977 (Box 64 (Broadside))
      Contains École supérieure des sciences économiques et commerciales (1974), and Galleria Antiope, Wolman (1977).
    - Press releases and flyers for miscellaneous exhibitions, 1971-1995 (Box 44, Folder 650)
    - Press clippings on Wolman's exhibitions, 1973-2008 (Box 44, Folder 651-652)
      - Fragile originals on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 830)
    - Press clippings on other artists' exhibitions, 1972-1997 (Box 44, Folder 653)
  - Editorial Work, 1960-1989
    - L'Entracte, unnumbered issue, circa 1960 (Box 45, Folder 654)
    - L'Officiel des antiquaires, issue no. 1, 1967- (Box 45, Folder 655)
    - L'Officiel des galeries
      - Advertisement "Lisez L'Officiel des galeries, visitez les galeries d'art", undated (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 754)
      - Issue no. 183, 1978- (Box 45, Folder 656)
      - Maquette of advertisement for François Dufrêne's exhibition La cantate des mots camés, [1977] (Box 45, Folder 657)
        [Possibly for publication in L'officiel des galeries .]
      - Maquette of advertisement for Quentin Quint's exhibition 157 acquarelles, 1989- (Box 45, Folder 658)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 659)
      - Newspaper clippings about L'Officiel des galeries, 1962-1981 (Box 45, Folder 660)
        - Fragile original on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 831)
      - Orphaned pages from various issues, 1974-1986 (Box 45, Folder 661)
        Largely advertisements for Wolman's exhibitions.
        - Fragile original on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 832)
      - Postcards and text for an installation on Claude Clavel, 1988- (Box 45, Folder 662)
        For the L'Officiel des galeries stand at the Foire internationale d'art contemporain.
      - Prints of photographs for publication, 1971 and undated (Box 45, Folder 663)
- Artworks, 1965-1992; Series VI; 6.5; (5 boxes) + 3 broadsides, 1 broadside oversize
  Organized into two subseries: Works by Gil J Wolman, and Works by Others.
  Series VI. largely consists of artwork by Wolman in the form of prints, photocopies, photographs, portfolios, drawings, and an original canvas. It offers limited documentation of the concepts and media explored by Wolman in his visual art from the 1960s to the 1980s, including "art scotch", copy art, and "séparation". The series also includes a small number of drawings, prints, and other artworks by other artists in Wolman's milieu.
  - Works by Gil J Wolman, circa 1965-1985
    Arranged alphabetically by genre.
    - Art scotch piece, circa 1965 (Box 46)
      24 x 35 cm on canvas. When creating his "art scotch", Wolman used tape to lift ink off newspaper or magazine pages, and remixed the printed words or images extracted with the tape on a new support, here a canvas.
    - Art scotch posters composite negatives, circa 1964-1966 (Box 68)
      Two composite negatives made of cellophane pressure-sensitive tape pieces placed between acetate sheets, used by Wolman to print posters advertising his art scotch. One features text and headlines transferred from newspapers, and appears as the background to the poster for Galerie Valerie Schmidt, Art Scotch 2: faux témoignages de Wolman (1966). The other features images of eyes and mouths, likely transferred from magazines, over blocks of text. 24 x 21 cm each. Both exhibit signs of degradation.
    - Art scotch poster prints, circa 1966 (Box 61 (Oversize), Folder 780)
    - Copy art "Autobuste", circa 1984 (Box 48, Folder 665)
      Two copies, caption: "Freud de Gauvin, séparation de Wolman, autobuste de Clavel".
    - Copy art ["Déchets d'oeuvre"], circa 1981 (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 788)
    - Copy art, untitled, circa 1980-1985 (Box 48, Folder 666-668)
      Three series, composed of overlapping press clippings, of a woman's portrait, and of manuscript notes.
      - Fragile original on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 833)
    - Drawings of stylized figures, ink on tracing paper, circa 1979 (Box 47, Folder 664)
      Biographical / Historical
      53 pages of drawings in style similar to Dühring Dühring.
    - Lithographs "La vie vraie", [1981] (Box 63 (Broadside))
      Two copies, one signed and numbered 18/80. 80 x 61 cm.
    - Photocopies [of art scotch rods?], undated (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 756)
    - Photograph of an art scotch piece, undated (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 757)
    - Photographs and collage "C'est le mouvement séparatiste qui provoque l'espace", circa 1978 (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 758)
    - Photograph "Vernissage à Grand Palais", [1981] October 15 (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 759)
      Composite photograph showing Wolman's mannequins séparés at the opening of the exhibition Retrospective: Wolman (Foire internationale d'art contemporain, Grand Palais, 1981), with a blank negative overlay. The right side of the photograph has been torn ("séparée"). Possibly a collaboration with Valentin Maria.
    - Portfolio "De quelques uns des portraits de poches réalisés par Wolman en 1974 entre le 26 janvier et le 3 février" (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 760)
      Self-published with Éditions inconnues, with an introduction by Christian Rigal on Wolman's copy art.
    - Portfolio "Quelques jours en août 1976, affiches restaurées", 1977 (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 761)
      Portfolio of fourty-eight posters printed to accompany the exhibition of the same name at Galerie Weiller.
    - Posters from "Quelques jours en août 1976, affiches restaurées", circa 1977 (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 762)
      Five posters from the "Quelques jours en Août 1976, affiches restaurées" series, featuring the restauration of some letters previously omitted from the printed text.
    - Poster "Pour la manifestation du 18 mai 79", [1979] (Box 69 (Broadside oversize))
      120 x 79 cm.
    - Poster series, untitled, undated (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 763)
      Series of six posters with text on white background.
    - Screen prints ["Artaud en finir"], [1972?] (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 789)
      Two copies, one signed and numbered 41/150. 65 x 50 cm.
    - Screen print "Décomposition (C'était 50 ans)", [1979] (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 790)
      Signed, with watermark of Editions Spiess. 65 x 50 cm.
    - Screen prints "Festival at Ford Boyard", [1967] (Box 65 (Broadside))
      Fourteen posters, presumably printed by Wolman, for the Festival de Fort Boyard (June 1967), an imaginary avant-garde art festival conceptualized by Wolman, Henri Chopin, Antonio Berni, Gianni Bertini, Julien Blaine, and others. Contains unique printings with varying colors and details of 4 posters featuring artworks by different artists: 9 printings featuring Blaine (including one printed on L'Humanité newspaper issue, dated 1967 June 10, front only); 1 printing featuring Bertini; 1 printing featuring Milos Urbasek; 3 printings featuring an unsigned artwork.
    - Screen print "Jacob ou la persuasion", [1972] (Box 59 (Oversize), Folder 764-765)
      Accompanied by a portfolio of prints, numbered copy 29/100, by artists participating to the exhibition Jacob our la persuasion - quatrième volet (Galerie Weiller, 1972).
    - Screen prints ["Je ne suis pas fou"], [1972?] (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 791)
      Two copies, one signed and numbered 31/40. 65 x 50 cm.
    - Screen print ["Vierge"], [1972?] (Box 62 (Oversize), Folder 792)
      Signed and numbered 94/150. 66 x 51 cm.
    - Screen print series, untitled, [1972] (Box 48, Folder 669)
      Signed and numbered 36/40, 28 x 21 cm. [Published in the serial Apeïros, edited by Roberto Altmann, according to the vendor inventory.]
    - Source material files "Document matériel", undated (Box 48, Folder 670-672)
      Includes mail art, flyers, photographs, envelopes, and paper fragments that may have been kept as source material for collages or photocopy art.
  - Works by Others, 1977-1992 and undated
    Arranged alphabetically by creator.
    - Altagor. Watercolor with stamped address and mottos, undated (Box 48, Folder 673)
    - Bodson, Guy. Photocopy art "Faites vous même un Wolman", 1989- (Box 48, Folder 674)
    - [Gilardi, Piero?]. Black and white abstract prints, undated (Box 48, Folder 675)
      Series of four drawings printed on recycled paper, signed in the back "Gilard[i]/[y] 123".
    - Koskas, George. Ink sketches, 1979-1992 (Box 48, Folder 676)
      Includes a paste-up for a flyer advertising the exhibition Saintaises (Galerie Raph, 1979), and sketches for a flyer advertising the exhibition Oriances (Galerie Raph, 1981).
    - [Koskas, George?]. Untitled gouache painting on paper, undated (Box 48, Folder 677)
    - Niotou, H[enri]. "Cm2 Niotou" pieces, 1977- (Box 48, Folder 678)
      Piece no. 284 of puzzle 01, and piece no. 23 of puzzle 03.
    - Wolman, Charlotte. Ink and pencil drawings, undated (Box 48, Folder 679)
    - Unknown, "Kluft" geometric drawings in ink on paper, undated (Box 48, Folder 680)
    - Unknown, collage, undated (Box 48, Folder 681)
- Audio Recordings, 1965-2010; Series VII; .21; (1 box + 3 record album storage)
  Boxes 49-52 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Series VII. contains audiocassettes and phonograph records featuring sound poetry by Wolman, François Dufrêne, and Jean Louis Brau, as well as the sound track to Wolman's film L'Anticoncept.
  - Brau, Jean Louis. Instrumentation verbale (Alga Marghen), 2010-; 1.0; (33 rpm) (Box 52 (record album storage), Folder 689)
  - Dufrêne, François. Cantate des mots camés (Éditions Achèle), [1983]; 1 (Box 49, Item barcode 39002104885257)
  - Wolman, Gil J. L'Anticoncept (Alga Marghen), 1999-; 1.0; (33 rpm) (Box 52 (record album storage), Folder 690)
  - Booklet of three sound poetry records (Éditions Achèle), circa 1965
    - Brau, Jean-Louis. Instrumentation verbale, 1964-11-14-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 50 (record album storage), Folder 683)
    - Dufrêne, François. Crirythme, 1965-04-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 50 (record album storage), Folder 684)
    - Wolman, Gil J. Mégapneumies, 1963-03-24-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 50 (record album storage), Folder 685)
  - Set of three records, 1965-09-23-
    Likely copies of the sound poetry records by Wolman, Dufrêne, and Brau released together by Éditions Achèle.
    - "FD", 1965-09-23-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 51 (record album storage), Folder 686)
    - "GJW", 1965-09-23-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 51 (record album storage), Folder 687)
    - "JLB", 1965-09-23-; 1.0; (45 rpm) (Box 51 (record album storage), Folder 688)
- Writings about Wolman, 1974-2011; Series VIII; .63; (2 boxes)
  Series VIII. contains essays, articles, theses, and dissertations analyzing Wolman's works. Typescripts of essays submitted to Charlotte Wolman in preparation for the retrospective volume Défense de mourir (Paris: Éditions Allia, 2001) constitute a signficant part of the series.
  Arranged alphabetically by author. Submissions and proofs for Défense de mourir are listed at the end under a separate heading.
  - Bugeaud, Patrick. "Wolman: Artiste séparatiste", master's thesis, 1987-03- (Box 53, Folder 691)
  - Bugeaud, Patrick. "Wolman hyper résumé", undated (Box 53, Folder 692)
  - Bugeaud, Patrick and Dominique Meens. "Wolman ou Les Inhumations; genre moral", 1995- (Box 53, Folder 693)
  - "Gill Wolman: Inventeur de l'Art Scotch", in 3M brochure no. 28, 1978- (Box 53, Folder 694)
  - Giroud, Michel. "Gil J. Wolman: entretien scotché Michel Giroud - Gil J. Wolman", printout with Wolman's corrections, After 1988 (Box 53, Folder 695)
  - Lepage, Jacques. "Anatomie de l'importance et l'influence de Raoul Hausmann", [1974] (Box 53, Folder 696)
  - "Les peintres parlents: Gil Wolman", in Les cahiers de la peinture no. 17, 1975-01- (Box 53, Folder 697)
  - Prieto, Graciela. Excerpts from "Écritures du sinthome", PhD dissertation, 2011- (Box 53, Folder 698)
  - Texts on sound poetry, undated (Box 53, Folder 699)
    Original grouping containing a typescript of Maurice Lemaître's short essay "Du Lettrisme à la mégapneumie", clippings on mégapneumie from unidentified publications, and a typescript by Noël Arnaud introducing recordings by Wolman, Jean-Louis Brau, and François Dufrêne.
  - Thieulin, Jérôme. "Étude du Fond Gil.J.Wolman au FRAC-Bourgogne: L'époque des «séparations» 1977-1980", master's thesis, 2003-2004 (Box 53, Folder 700)
  - Valensi, Michel. "Dix paroles après avoir lu Les Inhumations de Wolman", 1995- (Box 53, Folder 701)
    Accompanied by a thermofax typescript "Logique d'un promeneur" by Patrick Bugeaud on Dominique Meens' work L'ornitologie d'un promeneur.
    - Fragile original on thermal paper (Box 67, Folder 834)
  - Wolman, Barbara. "Quelques avis sur la vidéo", undated (Box 53, Folder 702)
  - Essays submitted for Défense de mourir (Paris: Éditions Allia, 2001)
    - Botz, Yves. "Tu vas la taire ta gueule", 2001- (Box 54, Folder 703)
    - Bouhours, Jean-Michel. "De l'anticoncept à l'anticoncept", [2001] (Box 54, Folder 704)
    - Latreille, Emmanuel. "Wolman sépare tout", 2001- (Box 54, Folder 705)
    - Meens, Dominique. "Wolman avant et après", [2001] (Box 54, Folder 706)
    - Semin, Didier. "C'est dans la pauvreté des choses qu'on fait la bonne soupe de l'oeuvre", [2001] (Box 54, Folder 707)
    - Incomplete set of proofs, 2001-06-05- (Box 54, Folder 708)
      Accompanied by correspondence between Emmanuel Latreille and Charlotte Wolman regarding the FRAC-Bourgogne's 2001 exhibit Gil Joseph Wolman: Les Ex-positions.
- Personal Papers, 1937-1995; Series IX; .42; (1 box)